

# Soma Utsumi

# **Platform Engineer**

- Tokyo, Japan
- github.com/soma00333
- soma00333.notion.site/Soma-Utsumi-32fff212315a4e9d894b704d52b23074

## **SUMMARY**

I'm a Senior Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience and a Platform Engineer with 2+ years of professional experience in Tokyo, Japan.

I engaged in the backend developments for enterprise applications and the operation of cloud infrastructures with

high-security requirements. I am proficient in developing with Go and gRPC, as well as managing infrastructures using GKE.

# **SKILLS**

## SRE

- SLI/SLO
- Datadog
- Observability

#### Platform Engineer

- GCP
- Kubernetes
- Terraform
- CI/CD
- Developer Experience

# **Backend Engineer**

- Go
- qRPC
- PostgreSQL
- Microservice

# **LANGUAGES**

- Japanese(Native)
- English(Business)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# 2024-04 -

# Freelance, Embedded SRE in AI/LLM Division

#### Present

#### LaverX Inc.

- I was involved in developing enterprise applications and infrastructures for the top 10 financial institutions in Japan.
- I deployed applications and infrastructures to the enterprise client's environments using the closed network, ensuring compliance with the highest security standards.

# 2023-11 -

# Freelance, Enabling SRE/Platform Engineer

## Present

enechain Corporation

- I was involved in the operation of GKE clusters with over 40 nodes and more than 350 pods.
- I created manifest and Terraform generator tools for developers, accelerating microservice development and cutting coding time by 90%.
- I rebuilt the Terraform infrastructures to improve execution speed and cost efficiency, resulting in a 50% reduction in execution time and a 50% reduction in costs.
- I standardized repository structures and branch strategies for manifests and applications, resulting in a 20% improvement in CI/CD speed.
- I introduced telepresence to the dev cluster to improve the developer experience of microservice developments.
- I redesigned the access control policies with high governance and security standards to ensure compliance with audits for the government.

# 2019-04 -Present

## CT0

# Industry Technology Inc.

- I developed the backend for the enterprise application, which provides over 60 services(.protos) to the largest real estate companies in Japan.
- I deployed applications and infrastructures that ensured enterprise security and governance standards.
- I migrated a legacy MySQL 5.7 to MySQL 8.0 (500 QPS), improving cost efficiency and performance.
- I designed SLIs and SLOs and created dashboards and monitors, which
  resulted in incident mitigation and early bug detection.
- I migrated from a modular monolith (100 RPS) to microservices, resulting in an increased release frequency.

# **EDUCATION**

## 2014 - 2018

# **Bachelor of Engineering**

## The University of Tokyo

 I designed a preoperative evaluation system for elderly patients using a generalized linear model.